<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Research | Marlie</title><link>https://marlietandoc.github.io/tag/research/</link><atom:link href="https://marlietandoc.github.io/tag/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Research</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://marlietandoc.github.io/media/icon_hu85feb84b9d98f8797ec82ae0eb98f4f2_1375536_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Research</title><link>https://marlietandoc.github.io/tag/research/</link></image><item><title>My brain in the palm of my hand</title><link>https://marlietandoc.github.io/fun_projects/brain/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marlietandoc.github.io/fun_projects/brain/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Memory errors in behavior, brains, and machines</title><link>https://marlietandoc.github.io/project/example/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marlietandoc.github.io/project/example/</guid><description>&lt;p>Information varies in how generalizable or specific it is across experiences. For example, as we encounter birds we can learn that there are shared features that link these experiences together (birds can fly and lay eggs). But at the same time, we can also learn that there are unique features that set experiences apart (flamingos are pink and have long legs). We tested whether or not people misremember things differently depending on whether or not it is shared or unique.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To do this, we created online memory games where participants memorized the colors of cartoon satellites. We then tested how people&amp;rsquo;s memory for colors were distorted based on whether or not that satellite part was shared or unique. We also trained a neural network model of the hippocampus on the same satellites to see if it the mode would also show memory biases.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;figure >
&lt;div class="d-flex justify-content-center">
&lt;div class="w-100" >&lt;img alt="Memory game visualization" srcset="
/project/example/memorygame_hu3bdd692245b977856dcf678c4fc086a5_1374677_f542a0e58eb9e898671c8af41b96dce9.webp 400w,
/project/example/memorygame_hu3bdd692245b977856dcf678c4fc086a5_1374677_30568d02fa5951d66ef4121fe8928f6a.webp 760w,
/project/example/memorygame_hu3bdd692245b977856dcf678c4fc086a5_1374677_1200x1200_fit_q100_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w"
src="https://marlietandoc.github.io/project/example/memorygame_hu3bdd692245b977856dcf678c4fc086a5_1374677_f542a0e58eb9e898671c8af41b96dce9.webp"
width="760"
height="532"
loading="lazy" data-zoomable />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In humans, we find that memory biases were the strongest for information that was shared across experiences (shared features). By examining how the hidden layers of a neural network model represent information, we find a strikingly similar effect where the model&amp;rsquo;s internal representations are also distorting shared features the most.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;figure >
&lt;div class="d-flex justify-content-center">
&lt;div class="w-100" >&lt;img alt="Main finding" srcset="
/project/example/finding_hu2836d793b2940ceb49afc0e2a2f3e7eb_410382_6c54e2805a79410b7aff6169b1f39e42.webp 400w,
/project/example/finding_hu2836d793b2940ceb49afc0e2a2f3e7eb_410382_f89b03094ce1937eb7cf6139d6a8013c.webp 760w,
/project/example/finding_hu2836d793b2940ceb49afc0e2a2f3e7eb_410382_1200x1200_fit_q100_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w"
src="https://marlietandoc.github.io/project/example/finding_hu2836d793b2940ceb49afc0e2a2f3e7eb_410382_6c54e2805a79410b7aff6169b1f39e42.webp"
width="760"
height="548"
loading="lazy" data-zoomable />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This shows that both human and machine learners, which are remarkable at learning how information is shared across many experiences, show memory biases that reflect learning of patterns&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This makes sense if we learn information across memories are related, it is more likely we will mix up the details. But if we learn that information is idioscynratic (something that ML models need to learn to prevent overfitting). This shows a perhaps negative outcome of an adaptive learning system.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We are now collecting high-resolution neuroimaging data (fMRI) where we will examine how these memory biases manifest from human brain activity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong> My Role: &lt;/strong> I led experimental design, programmed task-based experiments (e.g. memory games) in Javascript and Python, assisted in securing grant funding (&amp;gt;$200k), stimulus creation, develop, wrangled and analyzed data in R, collected data on Amazon Mechanical Turk. I also recently presented this work as a talk at
&lt;a href="https://www.sfn.org/meetings/neuroscience-2022" target="_blank">Neuroscience '22 in San Diego&lt;/a>
, one of the biggest science conferences in the world.
&lt;figure >
&lt;div class="d-flex justify-content-center">
&lt;div class="w-100" >&lt;img alt="SfN 2022 Talk" srcset="
/project/example/sfntalk_hu3bc24b6a760c3562e9b71ad8f4ea7671_434987_fe12c11cbbfa26d67258e27fe4a0503c.webp 400w,
/project/example/sfntalk_hu3bc24b6a760c3562e9b71ad8f4ea7671_434987_34710ba67f0e1f871b08e92d8f358dec.webp 760w,
/project/example/sfntalk_hu3bc24b6a760c3562e9b71ad8f4ea7671_434987_1200x1200_fit_q100_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w"
src="https://marlietandoc.github.io/project/example/sfntalk_hu3bc24b6a760c3562e9b71ad8f4ea7671_434987_fe12c11cbbfa26d67258e27fe4a0503c.webp"
width="706"
height="760"
loading="lazy" data-zoomable />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>MDRS '22 conference totes</title><link>https://marlietandoc.github.io/fun_projects/tote/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marlietandoc.github.io/fun_projects/tote/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Impacts of indoor air quality on cognitive performance</title><link>https://marlietandoc.github.io/project/iaq/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marlietandoc.github.io/project/iaq/</guid><description>&lt;p>Poor air quality is related to all sorts of health consequences. But only recently have we started to test how air quality impacts cognitive outcomes in real-time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We researched how CO2 (as well as essential oil emissions) are detrimental for certain kinds of decision-making. And found evidence that both CO2 (in a systematic review) and a common household product (essential oils) hurt decision-making. This work provides key insights into why ventilation is critical for building design, such as in workplaces, schools, and even high-stakes environment (like submarines and spaceships!), as decision-making may otherwise be impaired. See one of the lead investigators on this project
&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qnDQtBXge2o" target="_blank"> talk about the importance of indoor air quality with CityNews&lt;/a>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong> My Role: &lt;/strong>As a psychology researcher, my role on this project was to develop, code up (Python), and administer a battery of 6 tasks that tap into meaningful markers of cognitive perfroamnce, collaborate with engineers and chemists to design an experiment and conduct a thoughtful literature review, as well as to collect, and analyze behavioral data (A/B test). I worked closely with engineers to advocate for how human/user psychology works and interact while integrating their design constraints into our research plans. How do design experiments and surveys that humans can intuiively interact with. I also presented earlier versions of this work at a XSEED conference (Toronto, Canada), an initiative meant to tackle complex, multidisciplinary challenges.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Learning is better in the morning</title><link>https://marlietandoc.github.io/project/tod/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marlietandoc.github.io/project/tod/</guid><description>&lt;p>How do different brain states influence the ability to generalize what we know to new scenarios? Using a concept learning task, we assess the effect of time of day on generalization in 331 undergraduates who were brought into the lab either in the morning (9am) or evening (9pm). We found with better generalization in the morning than the evening. Consistent with work that the brain is in a lower state of lowered inhibition in the mornin, may facilitate spreading activation between otherwise separate memories, promoting generalization and transfer to new contexts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>suggesting that in the morning inhibition in the brain is reduced allowing you to transfer what you learned to new scenarios.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My role: Wrote the paper, made figures and visualizations (ggplot2, Illustrator), analyzed data and performed statistics (regression, correlation, ANOVA),
Example visualizations:&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>