<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Projects | Marlie</title><link>https://marlietandoc.github.io/project/</link><atom:link href="https://marlietandoc.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Projects</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://marlietandoc.github.io/media/icon_hu85feb84b9d98f8797ec82ae0eb98f4f2_1375536_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Projects</title><link>https://marlietandoc.github.io/project/</link></image><item><title>Memory errors in behavior, brains, and machines</title><link>https://marlietandoc.github.io/project/example/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marlietandoc.github.io/project/example/</guid><description>&lt;p>We created memory games where participants had to memorize the colors of different cartoon satellites.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;figure >
&lt;div class="d-flex justify-content-center">
&lt;div class="w-100" >&lt;img alt="Memory game visualization" srcset="
/project/example/memorygame_hu3bdd692245b977856dcf678c4fc086a5_1374677_f542a0e58eb9e898671c8af41b96dce9.webp 400w,
/project/example/memorygame_hu3bdd692245b977856dcf678c4fc086a5_1374677_30568d02fa5951d66ef4121fe8928f6a.webp 760w,
/project/example/memorygame_hu3bdd692245b977856dcf678c4fc086a5_1374677_1200x1200_fit_q100_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w"
src="https://marlietandoc.github.io/project/example/memorygame_hu3bdd692245b977856dcf678c4fc086a5_1374677_f542a0e58eb9e898671c8af41b96dce9.webp"
width="760"
height="532"
loading="lazy" data-zoomable />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We then tested how people&amp;rsquo;s memory for colors was distorted. We find that there were bigger memory biases for information that is shared across experiences, and weaker memory biases for more idiosyncratic information. By examining the neural activity of this information in a neural network model we find something similar, where the neural patterns in the model are more distorted for shared information that it is for idiosyncratic information.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;figure >
&lt;div class="d-flex justify-content-center">
&lt;div class="w-100" >&lt;img alt="Main finding" srcset="
/project/example/finding_hu2836d793b2940ceb49afc0e2a2f3e7eb_410382_6c54e2805a79410b7aff6169b1f39e42.webp 400w,
/project/example/finding_hu2836d793b2940ceb49afc0e2a2f3e7eb_410382_f89b03094ce1937eb7cf6139d6a8013c.webp 760w,
/project/example/finding_hu2836d793b2940ceb49afc0e2a2f3e7eb_410382_1200x1200_fit_q100_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w"
src="https://marlietandoc.github.io/project/example/finding_hu2836d793b2940ceb49afc0e2a2f3e7eb_410382_6c54e2805a79410b7aff6169b1f39e42.webp"
width="760"
height="548"
loading="lazy" data-zoomable />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We are currently collecting high-resolution neuroimaging data (fMRI) where we will examine how memory biases manifest in the human brain. We will then compare how memory representations in the artificial neural network are the same or different as memory representations in the brain.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong> My Role: &lt;/strong> I led experimental design, programmed task-based experiments (e.g. memory games) in Javascript and Python, assisted in securing grant funding (&amp;gt;$200k), stimulus creation, develop, wrangled and analyzed data in R, collected data on Amazon Mechanical Turk.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I also recently presented this work as a talk at
&lt;a href="https://www.sfn.org/meetings/neuroscience-2022" target="_blank">Neuroscience '22 in San Diego&lt;/a>
, one of the biggest science conferences in the world.
&lt;figure >
&lt;div class="d-flex justify-content-center">
&lt;div class="w-100" >&lt;img alt="SfN 2022 Talk" srcset="
/project/example/sfntalk_hu3bc24b6a760c3562e9b71ad8f4ea7671_434987_fe12c11cbbfa26d67258e27fe4a0503c.webp 400w,
/project/example/sfntalk_hu3bc24b6a760c3562e9b71ad8f4ea7671_434987_34710ba67f0e1f871b08e92d8f358dec.webp 760w,
/project/example/sfntalk_hu3bc24b6a760c3562e9b71ad8f4ea7671_434987_1200x1200_fit_q100_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w"
src="https://marlietandoc.github.io/project/example/sfntalk_hu3bc24b6a760c3562e9b71ad8f4ea7671_434987_fe12c11cbbfa26d67258e27fe4a0503c.webp"
width="706"
height="760"
loading="lazy" data-zoomable />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Impacts of indoor air quality on cognitive performance</title><link>https://marlietandoc.github.io/project/iaq/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marlietandoc.github.io/project/iaq/</guid><description>&lt;p>Poor air quality is related to all sorts of health consequences. But only recently have we started to test how air quality impacts cognitive outcomes in real-time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We researched how CO2 (as well as essential oil emissions) are detrimental for certain kinds of decision-making. And found evidence that both CO2 (in a systematic review) and a common household product (essential oils) hurt decision-making. This work provides key insights into why ventilation is critical for building design, such as in workplaces, schools, and even high-stakes environment (like submarines and spaceships!), as decision-making may otherwise be impaired. See one of the lead investigators on this project
&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qnDQtBXge2o" target="_blank"> talk about the importance of indoor air quality with CityNews&lt;/a>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong> My Role: &lt;/strong>As a psychology researcher, my role on this project was to develop, code up (Python), and administer a battery of 6 tasks that tap into meaningful markers of cognitive perfroamnce, collaborate with engineers and chemists to design an experiment and conduct a thoughtful literature review, as well as to collect, and analyze behavioral data (A/B test). I worked closely with engineers to advocate for how human/user psychology works and interact while integrating their design constraints into our research plans. How do design experiments and surveys that humans can intuiively interact with. I also presented earlier versions of this work at a XSEED conference (Toronto, Canada), an initiative meant to tackle complex, multidisciplinary challenges.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Learning is best in the morning</title><link>https://marlietandoc.github.io/project/tod/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marlietandoc.github.io/project/tod/</guid><description>&lt;p>How do different brain states influence the ability to generalize what we know to new scenarios? Using a concept learning task, we assess the effect of time of day on generalization in 331 undergraduates who were brought into the lab either in the morning (9am) or evening (9pm). We found with better generalization in the morning than the evening. Consistent with work that the brain is in a lower state of lowered inhibition in the mornin, may facilitate spreading activation between otherwise separate memories, promoting generalization and transfer to new contexts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>suggesting that in the morning inhibition in the brain is reduced allowing you to transfer what you learned to new scenarios.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My role: Wrote the paper, made figures and visualizations (ggplot2, Illustrator), analyzed data and performed statistics (regression, correlation, ANOVA),
Example visualizations:&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>